Inventory of the Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft correspondence
Hoover Institution Archives
Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft correspondence
1934-1936
XX086
Hoover Institution Archives
7 manuscript boxes 2.8 linear feet
Correspondence relating to grant applications for research projects. Includes correspondence with the Reichsamtsleitung of the Nationalsozialistischer deutscher Dozentenbund, the Kreisleitungen of the Nationalsozialistische deutsche Arbeiterpartei, the various police presidents of German cities, the Dozentenschaften of the various German universities and Technische Hochschulen, and private persons.
Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft.
Box 1-6
Shelf 8M.40
Access
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the library catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
Established in 1937, the Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft is a German government organization for promotion of academic research. The organization supported German scientific research through the issuing of grants to scientists before and during World War II. After a period of inactivity between 1945 and 1951, the organization was revived and continues to operate.
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence relating to grant applications for research projects. Includes correspondence with the Reichsamtsleitung of the Nationalsozialistischer deutscher Dozentenbund, the Kreisleitungen of the Nationalsozialistische deutsche Arbeiterpartei, various police presidents of German cities, the Dozentenschaften of various German universities and Technische Hochschulen, and private persons.
Nationalsozialistische deutsche Arbeiter-Partei.; Nationalsozialistischer deutscher Dozentenbund.; Education--Germany.; Research--Germany.; Universities and colleges--Germany.
- Abert-Antweiler, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 1: 1)
- Bass-von Berg, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 1: 2)
- Berger-Blüthgen, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 1: 3)
- Bomk-Bullig, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 1: 4)
- Bumm-Butschek, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 1: 5)
- Calker-Cramer, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 1: 6)
- Dänzer-Dumont, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 1: 7)
- Eberle-Ewers, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 2: 1)
- Fahlenbach-Fischer, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 2: 2)
- Flasche-Funck, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 2: 3)
- Gädke-Glavion, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 2: 4)
- Gollwitzer-Graze, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 2: 5)
- Grimm-Gutman, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 2: 6)
- Haack-von Ham, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 3: 1)
- Hangarter-Heidenreich, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 3: 2)
- Heidrich-Hering, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 3: 3)
- Herman-Höring, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 3: 4)
- Höttger-Hornig, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 3: 5)
- Horst-Huth, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 3: 6)
- Isenbeck-Just, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 3: 7)
- Kadletz-Klee, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 3: 8)
- Kleffner-Krallinger, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 3: 9)
- Kramer-Kier, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 4: 1)
- Laatsch-Lieber, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 4: 2)
- Lieberwirth-Lotthammer, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 4: 3)
- Lottermoser-Lutz, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 4: 4)
- Misch-Meyer, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 4: 5)
- Meyer-Moser, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 4: 6)
- Mrowka-Neuhaus, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 4: 7)
- Neuman-Otto, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 5: 1)
- Pagast-Pukowski, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 5: 2)
- Quellmaz-Reichle, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 5: 3)
- Reichmuth-Reusch, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 5: 4)
- Richarz-Ruprecht, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 5: 5)
- Salow-Siebel, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 5: 6)
- Siebenbaum-Succolowsky, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 5: 7)
- Schack von Wittenau-Schelsky, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 6: 1)
- Schenk-Schneider, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 6: 2)
- Schoon-Stange, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 6: 3)
- Stende-Sternberger, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 6: 4)
- Steudel-Thiele, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 6: 5)
- Thienhaus-Vogel, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 6: 6)
- Vogt-Weimann, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 7: 1)
- Weinschenk-Wilmsen, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 7: 2)
- Windermeier-Wüst, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 7: 3)
- Zastrau-Zwecker, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 7: 4)